eddiebauer.ca 2019-04-23

# Privacy And Security | Company Information | Eddie Bauer

### Overview

In 1920, Eddie Bauer wrote his business creed, a statement explaining the services he'd provide for his customers. We still follow this same creed today: "To give you such outstanding quality, value, service and guarantee that we may be worthy of your high esteem." Here at Eddie Bauer, we take this promise seriously and we firmly believe in your privacy and the security of your personal information. We are committed to using any information you give us in a responsible manner. You're very important to us and we want to provide you with a safe and secure online experience.

### Complete Privacy Policy

####  What Personal information does Eddie Bauer collect about me?

Personal information is information about an identifiable individual. Personal information includes such things as your name, address, age, income, date of birth, gender, financial information and credit records, as well as your opinions, preferences and purchase patterns.

We collect personal information only for the uses described in this privacy policy. We may update this policy from time to time and will notify you by posting such changes onour website and strongly encourage you to regularly check back.

We collect personal information in a number of ways: directly from you, indirectly from you, and occasionally from third parties.

###  Directly

When you purchase from Eddie Bauer or request a catalog, we collect information that you volunteer such as your name, email address, postal address, phone number and other information necessary to process your order or send you the catalog.

We collect the information you provide to us when you register for "My Account", enroll in our loyalty rewards program, participate in a contest or sweepstakes promotion, fill out a survey or questionnaire, or contact us (for example via email, "Ask Eddie" or "Live Chat".)

###  Indirectly

Every time you visit our website, we automatically collect your Internet Protocol service provider's address (or "IP address"), the Web page from which you came, and a record of your activity on our site. We may also collect information about your browser, such as screen resolution, installed plug-ins and fonts, and information about how your browser renders text.

Cookies are small text files that contain a unique identifier which is placed on your computer. When you visit a website, the website saves the file with a matching identifier. When you revisit the site days or weeks later, the site can recognize you by matching the cookie on your computer with the matching identifier in its database. For more information on "Cookies", see below.

We use mobile location analytics technology at our U.S. retail spaces to gain aggregate insights about customer behavior. The data collected is anonymous and works by sensing the presence of Wi-Fi enabled devices. No personal information is collected. This technology collects and hashes Media Access Control (MAC) addresses from Wi-Fi enabled devices that come in contact with our network equipment. In addition, this technology collects signal strength, time and date, the manufacturer of the device, and the name of a Wi-Fi network currently connected to the device, if applicable. A MAC address is a unique identifier assigned to every mobile device and is not the device's phone number. Collection of mobile location information only occurs when a device's Wi-Fi setting is turned on.

#### How do you use my information?

The information we receive allows us to tailor our product offer and improve your shopping experience, making shopping easier and more enjoyable. It also enables us to process your purchases, confirm your orders, customize the content and layout of our pages, notify you about updates to our websites and products, and provide you with marketing information.

The information you supply to us is added to our customer database. You may receive periodic mailings or telephone calls from us about new products and services, discounts, special promotions or upcoming events. If you do not want to receive such mailings or telephone calls from us, pleaseclick here for contact information.

We use mobile location analytics technology to develop anonymous and aggregated reporting and to gain a better understanding of our customers' preferences. This information might be used, for example, to improve our store layouts or the timing of promotions and sales. If you wish to opt out of participation and delete existing mobile location data, pleaseclick here

###  Interest-Based Advertising and Opt Out

We may provide your personally-identifiable information, including your name, address, email address, as well as a record of any transactions you conduct on our website or offline with us with advertising partners and their service providers in order to deliver advertising tailored to your interests when you are online. Our advertising partners have committed to make the data we provide anonymous before using it to deliver ads online.

We may transfer your personal information to entities outside Eddie Bauer, such as our vendors, suppliers and agents who assist us in serving you and may use cookies on our behalf. Our service providers may be located outside of Canada and may be required to disclose your personal information under the laws of their jurisdiction. You may contact us for information about our policies and practices regarding service providers to whom we have transferred your personal information and their locations (see Contact Information, below).

We may also partner with other service providers that use anonymized information about your visits to our website, your interaction with our products and services, and your visits to other websites to serve Eddie Bauer and third party ads targeted to your interests on other websites. This information is collected through the use of cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies. To learn more about these practices or to opt out of having this information used by our third-party advertising partners to serve ads targeted to your interests, please visit the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada by[clicking here](https://www.aboutads.info/). To opt out of the online advertisements provided directly by Eddie Bauer,click here. If you delete your cookies, use a different browser, or buy a new computer, you will need to renew your opt-out choice.

###  Other Uses and Opt Out

In some cases we may provide your name and address to a select group of companies whose products you may find of interest. If you do not want us to share this information with these companies, we can add your name to our "do-not-share" list. Pleaseclick here for contact information.

We periodically send you email about new products and services, discounts, special promotions or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such emails in the future, pleaseclick here for contact information, or click the "unsubscribe" link on any promotional email you receive from us. Please note: In order to process your purchases we may send you a confirmation email or we may contact you by mail or telephone if we have questions about your order.

In some instances, we use third party companies to help us provide our products and services to you, to assist us in managing customer information, to fulfill promotions and to communicate with you. Some of these companies are given access to some or all of the information you provide to us, and some may use cookies on our behalf. These companies are contractually-restricted from using your information in any manner other than in helping us to provide you with the products and services available from Eddie Bauer.

We may share information with governmental agencies or other companies assisting us in fraud prevention or investigation. We may do so when: (1) permitted or required by law; or, (2) trying to protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud or unauthorized transactions; or, (3) investigating fraud which has already taken place. The information is not provided to these agencies or companies for marketing purposes.

#### Companies other than Eddie Bauer

Our privacy policy does not apply to companies other than Eddie Bauer. Companies other than Eddie Bauer are sometimes identified on our website, catalog or marketing materials. If you make a purchase from another company's catalog or website, the information you provide to that company, such as your credit card number and contact information, is provided to that company and not to Eddie Bauer. Providing this information to the company enables your transaction with the other company to take place. However, you should know that the company may, if you do not advise them to the contrary, share your name and postal and email addresses with third parties, including Eddie Bauer. You should also know that these companies have their own privacy and data collection practices and are not covered by the Eddie Bauer privacy statement.

For more information, including privacy policies, regarding such companies please see that company's home page and click on their Information link; or review the customer service section of any catalog you may receive from that company.

### For Our Customers Using the Internet

#### What are "cookies" and how does Eddie Bauer use them?

A "cookie" is a small data file stored on your computer. At Eddie Bauer, we place a unique identifier in the cookie and use the cookie to connect your computer with the information we store for you in our database. Some examples of the data we store in our database includes your account preferences, items added to your shopping bag, user-specific information on pages accessed, and previous visits to our site. Through cookies we may: alert you to new areas that we think might be of interest to you when you return to our site; record past activity at our site; provide advertisements that are tailored to your interests; or, customize Web page content.

We do not use cookies to store any of your personal or financial information on your computer.

We recognize that you have a choice to refuse cookies. However, by choosing to accept an Eddie Bauer cookie you allow us to maintain the preferences stored in your Eddie Bauer "My Account" and process your order. If you choose not to accept the cookie, purchasing is not possible on the Eddie Bauer site.

In addition to cookies, we or our partners may also use similar technologies like web beacons, HTML5 local storage, "Flash" cookies, statistical identification, and cross-device tracking (which relies on distinguishing technical characteristics of your browser or device).

If you are shopping Eddie Bauer and are having difficulty adding product to your shopping bag or completing your order, please check your privacy settings in your browser. If you do not wish to change your privacy settings to "Medium" and you are currently using the "Medium High" or "High" settings, you may choose to override your current cookie handling practices for individual sites that you specify, including eddiebauer.com and eddiebaueroutlet.com. Pleaseclick here for instructions on how to override your normal cookie handling practices. If you prefer not to change your privacy settings or override your cookie handling practices, you can, as always, place your order by phone at 1-888-495-5170.

#### How can I update my information?

We provide you access to the following information if you send us an email, call us or write to us:

  * Financial information (such as credit card account information)
  * Eddie Bauer customer identifier information (customer number or password)
  * Transaction information (dates on which you made purchases, amounts and types of Purchases)
  * Contact information (name, address, phone number)

We provide you with the ability to delete personally identifiable information if you send us an email, call us or write to us.

We evaluate each request and will reply in an appropriate manner and in a form of communication that ensures the security of the information you have requested. Any questions, pleasecontact us. 

#### How do I know my information is secure?

We have appropriate security measures in place to protect against the loss or theft, or unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use, or modification of information that we have collected from you so you can feel comfortable and secure when shopping. We use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving your personal information. On the Internet, when you see either a solid key icon or a locked padlock icon at the lower portion of your browser window, this indicates that the site is secured through Secure Sockets Layer (SSL). Pages requesting personal information should always have one of these icons. If you do not see one of these icons, please contact us to complete your transaction over the phone by calling 1-888-495-5170. When you apply on-line for an Eddie Bauer Charge Card, we will direct you to the Comenity Bank website. See the[Comenity.net](https://www.comenity.net/) website for information on its privacy statement.

### How to Report Fraud

You can help us identify attempts at fraud.

Eddie Bauer will never ask you for sensitive personal information in an email.

If you receive a suspicious email appearing to come from Eddie Bauer, such as one requesting that you confirm personal information like your credit card number, or if you have received an email implying that it has been sent by Eddie Bauer after you have Opted Out of receipt of Eddie Bauer emails, you may forward the suspicious email to[abuse@eddiebauer.com.](mailto:abuse@eddiebauer.com)

You should not respond directly to suspicious email. And do not click on or open any hyperlink embedded in the suspicious email.

There are a few common features of fraudulent emails that can help you identify them as spam. The two most frequent are:  

  1. a) receiving an email that contains mistakes such as misspelled words or grammatical errors, and
  2. b) receiving an email that asks for your confidential information or asks you to take immediate action on your account.

We encourage all of our customers to protect themselves and their information:  

  1. a) do not share your credentials or account information with any third party, and
  2. b) make sure that your system is properly patched, running anti-virus and a personal firewall.

If you have already provided information in response to a suspicious email that appeared to have been sent by Eddie Bauer, you may report the suspicious email by forwarding it to[abuse@eddiebauer.com.](mailto:abuse@eddiebauer.com).  

For more information on how to protect yourself and your personal information, you can visit the Canadian Anti-Fraud Centre at[http://www.antifraudcentre-centreantifraude.ca/index-eng.htm](https://www.antiphishing.org/resources/overview/).  

Thank you for helping us monitor and prevent fraud.

#### Children's Policy

Eddie Bauer does not seek to solicit information from anyone under the age of thirteen (a "Child"). If a Child submits information to us and we know that the person submitting the information is a Child, we will not use it for any purpose. We will delete the information as soon as we discover it and we will not disclose it to third parties.

###  Contact Information

Feel free to contact us for any reason, including a request to be added to or taken off a list, or if you have any questions or concerns. Please note: When you contact us, please provide your name and address exactly as it appears on correspondence you have received from us.

####  By Postal Mail

####  By Phone

#### By Email

If for any reason you would like to unsubscribe from either or both of our email programs, please follow the instructions below:

If you prefer not to receive Eddie Bauer catalogs from us, please[contact us](mailto:CustomerCare@csc.eddiebauer.com?subject=Unsubscribe%20Catalogs) or call 1-888-495-5170. Please include your full name and mailing address as it appears on your catalog. We will remove your name from our mailing list as soon as possible. Please recognize that you may receive another catalog before we are able to remove you. If you wish to be placed on our "Do Not Call" list, please let us know during the call,[ contact us](mailto:CustomerCare@csc.eddiebauer.com?subject=Please%20Add%20To%20Do%20Not%20Call%20List) or call 1-888-495-5170.

We also, on occasion, share a portion of our catalog mailing list with other reputable organizations. If you wish to have your name and address not shared with other organizations, please[contact us](mailto:CustomerCare@csc.eddiebauer.com?subject=Do%20Not%20Share%20Name%20and%20Address) or call 1-888-495-5170.
